NATHAN SCHEPERLE

DATA SCIENTIST

Charlotte, NC

T: 417-379-2099 // E: Nathan.Scheperle@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Aug. 2018 - May 2020 DUKE UNIVERSITY

MS in Data Science

GPA: 3.8

Cohort social chair

Coursework including machine learning, NLP, high dimensional data analysis, and Bayesian modeling

Aug. 2011 - May 2015

UNIVERSITY OF ARKANSAS

BS in Mathematics and Economics, Physics minor

summa cum laude

Honors: Phi Beta Kappa, Dean's List

Research:

"Robust Krylov Subspaces"

"Socioeconomic Indicators of Food Bank Clientele"

Sep. 2013 - July 2014

LONDON SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS AND POLITICAL SCIENCE

General Course - Junior year abroad

Mathematics and economics

EXPERIENCE

DUKE UNIVERSITY Jan. 2019 - Present

DURHAM, NC

Graduate Research Assistant

Department of Economics

Processed, cleansed, and merged manufacturing industry data for economic analysis on Teradata

Duke Clergy Health Initiative

Data engineering and automation for survey analysis through data pipeline development and relational database management

June 2019 - Aug. 2019 WELLS FARGO

CHARLOTTE.NC

Data Science Intern

Modeled mortgage bid tape auction data to optimize asset acquisition strategy using Python and Spark

July 2015 - July 2018

GENERAL MOTORS

CHANDLER. AZ

Data Analyst and BI Software Developer

- Developed database and business solutions to reduce warranty claims and improve quality of GM vehicles.
- Improved throughput of Global Analysis Reporting Tool application by 40% through performance analysis and query
- Collaborated on developing and executing strategy to migrate application database from SAS's SPDS database management system to IBM's DB2.

PROFILE

Curious and calculating data scientist fresh out of graduate school with 3 years of industry experience. Successful history of identifying patterns, making interpretations, and producing reports from diverse data. Skills in data management, automation, and software development practices.

SKILLS

Python SQL Spark Shell scripting R SAS **AWS**

CERTIFICATIONS

- SAS Base Programmer for SAS 9
- SAS Advanced Programmer for SAS 9